Dennou Boukenki
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Series Composition
Sekijima Mayori
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Takatori Hideaki
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
Director
Okajima Kunitoshi
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
Chief Director
Negishi Hiroshi
Production
아이들은 최후의 작전으로 매지컬 레일을 발사하고 데리트로스 성을 직접 공격하기로 했다.
Kento and his friends decided to do a final attack to Deletloss Castle directly by using Magical Rail.
Kento dan teman-temannya mencoba menggunakan strategi terakhirnya, yaitu menyerang langsung Deletloss Castle dengan Magical Rail.
그러나 가짜 글라디온 셋의 방해에 부딛혀 작전을 실패할 뻔 했다.
But the operation was about to fail because of three imitation Gladions' interruption.
Namun, rencananya hampir gagal akibat gangguan dari para Gladion palsu.
그 때...
Right at the moment...
Pada saat itu...
슬픔을 극복하고 켄토는 데리트로스 성을 파괴하는 데에 성공한다.
After overcoming the sorrow, Kento finally manages to destroy Deletloss Castle.
Setelah melewati keseihannya, Kento akhirnya berhasil menhancurkan Deletloss Castle.
악마의 진화! 다크 글라디온
Evolution of Devil!
Dark Gladion
Evolusi Iblis! Dark Gladion!
역시 틀림없습니다. 데리트로스 게이트의 소멸이 확인되었습니다.
I find no error in that Deletloss Gate's destruction is confirmed.
Tidak salah lagi. Hilangnya Deletloss Gate sudah dikonfirmasi.
그럼 아이들은?
Then how about the children?
Lalu, bagaimana dengan anak-anak?
자율 관리 프로그램 엔제 기동중.
Booting the autonomos management program Enge.
Program Kendali Mandiri Enge sedang berjalan.
무사합니다. 모두 매지컬 게이트에 돌아왔습니다.
They are safe! They're back in Magical Gate.
Mereka aman! Mereka semua sudah kembali ke Magical Gate.
영상 회선이 복구되었습니다. 스크린에 띄웁니다.
Video line is up at last. I'll put on the screen.
Jalur video sudah dipulihkan. Akan kutampilkan di layar.
띄우겠습니다.
Putting it up.
Tampilkan.
매지컬 스테이션입니다.
Magical Station.
Ini adalah Magical Station
세 프로그램으로 지켜지고 있는 모양입니다.
It is protected by three programs.
yang sedang dilindungi oleh tiga program.
가륜입니다.
Garyun.
와이버리온입니다.
Wyverion.
글라디온이야!
Hey, that's Gladion!
Itu Gladion!
글라디온...
Gladion...
카이토...
Kaito...
켄토...
Kento...
아오이!
Aoi!
들리는가! 아오이!
Do you hear me? Aoi!
Apa kau mendengarku, Aoi?!
통신 회선에 장애. 여기서 통신을 보낼 수는 없습니다.
There is an obstacle in the communication line. We cannot initate a communication here.
Ada gangguan pada jalur koneksinya. Kita tidak bisa berkomunikasi dari sini.
아오이...
Aoi...
저 목소리는 데리트로스! 역시, 류토, 넌 데리트로스였구나!
That voice is Deletloss'! Ryuto was Deletloss from the start after all!
Itu suara Deletloss! Ryuto, ternyata selama ini kau itu Deletloss, ya?!
네가 원하는 대로 되는 일은 없을 것이다! 현실 세계는 우리가 지키겠다!
You're not doing as you want! We will protect the real world!
Takkan kubiarkan kau berbuat seenaknya! Kami akan melindungi dunia nyata!
승부다! 데리트로스!
This is a match, Deletloss!
Ayo bertanding, Deletloss!
방해하지 마시게나, 글라디온.
Try and stop me, Gladion.
Kau tak akan menggangguku, Gladion.
내 백만 년의 바람, 데이터노이드에의 진화를!
I will evolve to Datanoid and achieve my million year long ambition!
Aku akan berevolusi menjadi Datanoid dan meraih ambisiku selama sejuta tahun ini!
현실 세계로의 문을!
The door to the real world!
Akan kubuka pintu menuju dunia nyata!
느긋하게 이 데리트로스에게 이길 수 있으리라고 생각하시나. 멍청한 놈.
Do you really think you can defeat me Deletloss optimistically? How pathetic.
Apa kau benar-benar berpikir kau bisa mengalahkan Deletloss? Bodoh sekali.
그래. 인류의 말살은 너로 시작해 주겠다!
Sure, then. Obliteration of humankind begins with you!
Boleh saja. Akan kumusnahkan umat manusia dari kalian!
하자! 쟌! 카이토!
Let's do this! Jean! Kaito!
Ayo kita lakukan ini! Jean! Kaito!
-응!
-Right!
-Baiklah!
켄토는?
Hey, where's Kento?
Dimana Kento?
여, 여긴!
Diverland...!
T-tempat ini...!
아야야야...
Ouch...
Aduh, duh, duh...
나오키!
Naoki!
어, 쇼우?
Hey, Shou!
Loh, Shou?
어? 나 분명히 드라그온하고 같이...
I thought I was perished with Dragwon...
Loh? Kupikir aku menghilang dengan Dragwon...
우리 다이브아웃되어 다이버랜드에 돌아왔나 봐.
We've been dived out and returned to Diverland.
Sepertinya kita telah dive out dan kembali ke Diverland.
그럼 그건...
Then that means...
Y-yang berarti...
켄토 놈, 해 낸 거야! 데리트로스 성을 파괴한 거야!
Kento did it! He destroyed Deletloss Castle!
Kento berhasil! Ia berhasil menghancurkan Deletloss Castle!
맞아, 분명 그랬을 거야.
Yeah, that must be it.
Ya, pasti begitu.
근데 다른 얘들은? 데리트로스는 어떻게 됐어?
But how about other children? What about Deletloss?
Tapi, bagaimana dengan yang lain? Apa yang terjadi pada Deletloss?
월드 링크 관리국에 가 보자. 뭔가 알게 되겠지.
Let's go to the administration center. We'll find out something there.
Ayo pergi ke Stasiun Pengendali. Kita pasti akan mengetahui sesuatu di sana.
그래!
Sure!
Ayo!
샤이닝 볼트!
Shining Bolt!
다크 블래스터!
Dark Blaster!
웹체인지! 와이버리온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Wyverion, Fighter Mode!
하울링 게이저!
Howling Geyser!
다크 발칸!
Dark Vulcan!
지금이야!
Now!
Sekarang!
브레이크 참!
Break Slash!
뭐야?!
What the?!
Apa?!
그 정도의 힘으로 이 데리트로스를 쓰러뜨린다고? 웃기지 마라!
You're going to take me down with that power? You must be joking!
Kau akan mengalahkanku dengan kekuatan seperti ini? Jangan bercanda!
다크 매그넘!
Dark Magnum!
다크니스 슛!
Darkness Shoot!
-켄토!
-Kento!
이걸로 끝이다! 글라디온!
You're going down right now, Gladion!
Inilah akhirmu, Gladion!
그렇군. 데이터 생명체로 진화해 전뇌세계에서 빠져나와 현실 세계를 직접 파괴한다니.
I see. It's going to evolve to a data lifeform, get out of the cyber world and destroy the real world by itself.
Jadi begitu. Ia akan berevolusi menjadi makhluk data, keluar dari dunia maya dan menghancurkan dunia nyata secara langsung.
이것이 데리트로스의 진짜 목적이었던 건가.
That was Deletloss' true intention.
Jadi itu tujuan Deletloss yang sesungguhnya.
안 됩니다. 데리트로스가 메모리를 잠궜습니다. 이렇게는 아이들을 구출할 수가...
There's nothing we can do. Deletloss has locked the memory. We can't rescue children like this...
Tidak bisa. Deletloss telah mengunci memorinya. Kalau begini, kita tidak bisa menolong anak-anak...
누나, 다이탈리온 프로그램은?
Sis, how is Ditalion program?
Kakak, bagaimana keadaan program Ditalion?
회수한 웹나이트 프로그램은 전부 복구중이야. 아직 기동할 수 없어.
We're recovering the programs we've retrieved. They cannot be booted yet.
Kita sedang memulihkan program-program yang kita terima. Mereka masih belum bisa beroperasi.
젠장!
Damn!
Sial!
박사님! 레스큐 프로그램! 개발중인 네오 매지컬 백신을 써 봅시다!
Professor! Use the rescue program! Let's try Neo Magical Vaccine in development!
Profesor! Gunakan program penolongnya! Ayo kita gunakan Neo Magical Vaccine yang masih dalam tahap pengembangan.
그거라면 데리트로스에게 효과가 있을 것입니다.
It will have some effect on Deletloss.
Seharusnya itu bisa menimbulkan suatu efek pada Deletloss.
시험 단계인 백신이지만 별 수 없지.
It's still in an examination, but that's the only option we have.
Itu masih vaksin dalam tahap uji coba, tapi apa boleh buat.
쿠라치 군!
Kurachi, do it!
Kurachi, lakukan!
알겠습니다.
Got it.
Baik.
네오 매지컬 백신 셋트.
Neo Magical Vaccine set.
Neo Magical Vaccine, disiapkan.
목표, 데리트로스. 발사.
Target, Deletloss. Shoot.
뭐야?!
What's that?!
Apa itu?!
-지금이야, 카이토! 하자!
-알았어, 형!
-Right now, Kaito! Let's
-do this, bro!
-Sekarang saatnya, Kaito! Ayo!
-Iya, Kak!
글라디온, 빅토리 모드!
Gladion, Victory Mode!
웹체인지! 와이버리온, 윙 모드!
Webchange! Wyverion, Wing Mode!
빅토리 글라디온!
Victory Gladion!
빅토리 맥시마 발동!
Victory Maxima activate!
Victory Maxima diaktifkan!
그란블레이드!
Granblade!
-승부다, 데리트로스!
-하자!
-It's a match, Deletloss!
-We'll do this!
-Lawan kami, Deletloss!
-Ayo kita lakukan ini!
다크 발칸!
Dark Vulcan!
뭐야?!
What's this?!
Apa?!
빅토리 참 맥시마!
Victory Slash Maxima!
빅토리 슛 맥시마!
Victory Shoot Maxima!
매지컬 게이트에서 뭔가 폭발했습니다.
Something has exploded inside Magical Gate.
Sesuatu telah meledak di dalam Magical Gate.
박사님, 이것은!
Professor, look at this!
Profesor, lihat ini!
이제 어떠냐, 데리트로스!
How's that, Deletloss!
Bagaimana, Deletloss!
혀, 형! 봐봐!
Hey, brother! Look at that!
K-kakak! Lihat!
뭐야?! 맥시마의 연속 공격으로도 쓰러지지 않은 건가!
What the?! He's still standing despite the continuous Maxima attacks!
Apa?! Ia masih belum kalah walaupun sudah diserang dengan serangan Maxima berturut-turut!
절대 용서할 수 없다!
I will not forgive you!
Aku tidak akan memaafkanmu!
이 궁극의 프로그램, 데리트로스에게 상처를 입히는 것은!
How dare you try to damage the ultimate program Deletloss?!
Berani-beraninya kau melukai program terunggul, Deletloss ini?!
뭐야?!
What's that?!
Apa?!
왜냐. 어째서 데이터노드로 진화하지 못하는 건가!
Why. Why am I not evolving to Deletloss?!
Kenapa? Kenapa aku tidak bisa bervolusi ke Datanoid?!
이미 모든 조건은 충족했을 텐데.
I should have prepared everything by now.
Padahal semua persyaratannya sudah kupenuhi.
뭐가 부족한 것인가!
What do I lack?!
Apa lagi yang kurang dari aku?!
데이터노이드, 궁극의 진화 형태가 된다면 글라디온 따위는!
When I evolve into a Datanoid, the form of ultimate evolution, Gladion won't stand a chance!
Ketika aku bervolusi menjadi Datanoid, wujud dari evolusi terunggul, Gladion pun tidak akan berdaya!
유우키 켄토. 글라디온과 마음의 정으로 묶인 웹다이버.
Yuuki Kento. An Webdiver tied to Gladion with the spirit.
Yuuki Kento. Seorang Webdiver yang jiwanya terikat dengan Gladion.
마음이라! 그래! 그것이 진화를 향한 마지막 관문이군!
Spirit! That's it! That's the last gate to the evolution!
Jiwa? Itu dia! Itulah kunci terakhir dari evolusi ini!
그렇다면!
Well then!
Kalau begitu!
글라디온! 넌 비겁할 뿐이다!
Gladion! You are coward!
Gladion! Kau adalah pengecut!
뭐라?!
What?!
Apa kau bilang?!
넌 백만 년 전의 복수를 하기 위해 유우키 켄토를 이용했다!
You used Yuuki Kento to have a revenge for the incident million years ago!
Kau memanfaatkan Yuuki Kento untuk membalaskan dendam kejadian sejuta tahun yang lalu!
켄토를 이용하다니? 아니다! 켄토는 소중한 친구로 나와 함께 싸우는 전사다!
I used him? Impossible! Kento is an important friend of mine who is also an warrior!
Aku memanfaatkannya? Bukan! Dia temanku yang berharga dan pejuang yang bertarung bersamaku!
인류를 구한다고? 흥, 그렇게 말하자면 네가 지켜야 하는 인류 중 하나,
Protect the humans, you said. Isn't Kento one of those who you have to protect?
Menolong umat manusia, katamu? Hm, kau bilang begitu, tapi Yuuki Kento, yang seharusnya kau tolong,
유우키 켄토를 위험한 전투에 끌어들이지 않았느냐.
Didn't you brought him into the dangerous battles?
malah kau libatkan dalam pertarungan yang berbahaya!
유우키 켄토가 지금까지 살 수 있었던 것은 단지 운이 좋았을 뿐이다!
He could live only because he was lucky until now!
Ia bisa bertahan hidup hingga saat ini karena beruntung saja!
그러나 이제 그런 일이 계속 일어날 수는 없지. 너나 나, 살아남는 건 단 하나!
But not any more, no. Between you and me, one shall stand and one shall fall!
Tapi, selanjutnya tidak akan seperti itu. Yang tetap hidup hanya satu; antara kau atau aku!
글라디온?
Gladion?
어쩔 생각이냐?!
What are you going to do?!
Apa yang akan kau lakukan?!
바라던 대로 백만 년 전 결투의 결판을 내겠다.
We will have the decisive battle for the million-year-long war as you wished.
Sesuai keinginanmu, akan kita selesaikan pertarungan sejuta tahun yang lalu.
우리 결판을 낼 딱 좋은 곳이 있다. 바로 그 곳!
And there is a place perfect for that. You know where I am talking about!
Kita selesaikan di tempat itu. Tempat yang cocok untuk pertarungan kita!
달아날 셈이냐! 샤이닝 볼트!
Are you going to run away?! Shining Bolt!
Takkan kubiarkan kau kabur! Shining Bolt!
끼어들지 마라! 다크 발칸!
Don't interrupt me! Dark Vulcan!
Sia-sia saja! Dark Vulcan!
기다리고 있겠다, 글라디온!
I'll be waiting, Gladion!
Aku menunggumu, Gladion!
달아날 셈이냐! 따라가자, 글라디온!
You're not running away! Let's follow him, Gladion!
Kau tidak akan kabur! Ayo kita kejar, Gladion!
왜 그래? 글라디온? 글라디온!
What's the problem? Gladion! Gladion, respond!
Ada apa? Gladion? Gladion!
진화의 때가 왔다. 나는 데이터노이드가 기다리는 현실 세계로 향한다.
It's time for the evolution at last. I am headed to the real world where my Datanoid will be waiting.
Tibalah saatnya untuk berevolusi. Aku akan menjadi Datanoid dan membuka pintu menuju dunia nyata.
내 고향, 행성 쿠리아에서!
In my birthplace, in planet Kuria!
Di tempat aku lahir, planet Kuria!
Brought to you by Subdiver
뭐가 문제야, 글라디온? 글라디온!
What's the problem, Gladion? Hey, Gladion!
Ada masalah apa, Gladion? Gladion!
가자, 글라디온! 데리트로스하고 최후의 결판을 내러 가자!
Let's go, Gladion! Let's settle this up with Deletloss for once and all!
Ayo pergi, Gladion! Kita selesaikan ini dengan Deletloss terakhir kalinya!
켄토.
Kento.
켄토! 카이토!
Kento! Kaito!
왜 그랬어, 글라디온!
Why did you do that, Gladion?!
Apa maksudnya ini, Gladion?!
헤어질 때가 왔다, 켄토.
It's time to separate, Kento.
Saatnya kita berpisah, Kento.
뭐, 뭔 소리야. 데리트로스하고 결판을 봐야 하잖아!
What are you talking about? We still have the final match against Deletloss!
A-apa yang kau bilang?! Kita akan bertarung melawan Deletloss, kan?
녀석을 쓰러뜨리고 우주를 구해야 해잖아!
We must take him down and save the universe!
Kita akan mengalahkannya dan menyelamatkan alam semesta, kan?!
데리트로스와의 결판은 보겠다. 단지 나 혼자 갈 뿐이다.
I will have the final match. But only by myself.
Aku akan menyelesaikan pertarungan dengannya. Namun, hanya aku sendiri yang pergi.
뭔 소리야! 데리트로스가 말한 게 신경쓰이는 거야? 나도 전사야!
That's nonsense! Does what Deletloss said bother you? I am a warrior too, you know!
Kenapa?! Apa kau khawatir pada apa yang Deletloss katakan tadi? Akupun juga pejuang!
정의를, 우주를 구하기 위해서라면 난 어떻게 되어도 상관 없어!
I don't care how I end up, if it is for the justice and for the protection of the universe!
Kalau untuk kebenaran, dan untuk melindungi alam semesta, aku tidak peduli apa yang terjadi padaku nantinya!
켄토!
Kento!
그런 슬픈 소리는 하지 말아줬으면 한다, 켄토.
Please don't say sad things like that, Kento.
Jangan katakan hal muram seperti itu, Kento.
우리는 세계의 사람들을, 그 생명을 지키기 위해 계속 싸워오지 않았니.
Didn't we always fought for the people of the world, and to protect their lives?
Bukankah kita selalu bertarung untuk melindungi orang-orang di dunia?
그래도... 그래도!
But... still...!
Tapi... tetap saja...!
켄토. 나는 항상 생각해 왔다. 나는 대체 뭘 위해 데리트로스하고 싸우고 있는가 하고.
Kento. I've always been thinking. Why am I fighting against Deletloss?
Kento. Aku selalu berpikir. Untuk apa aku bertarung melawan Deletloss?
물론, 정의를 위해서다. 그러나 그것 뿐만은 아니다. 그런 느낌이 항상 있었다.
Of course, it's for justice. But that's not all. I always thought there was something else.
Tentu saja, untuk membela kebenaran. Tapi, tidak hanya itu. Aku merasa, masih ada alasan yang lain.
데리트로스에게 복수하기 위해? 그건 아니다.
To seek my revenge on Deletloss? No, that will be a nonsense.
Untuk membalaskan dendamku pada Deletloss? Tidak, bukan itu.
데리트로스를 쓰러뜨린다고 해도 쿠리아 행성은 돌아오지 않을 테니까.
People of planet Kuria won't come back even if I take Deletloss down.
Sekalipun aku mengalahkannya, penduduk planet Kuria tidak akan kembali.
나는 원래의 인간 모습으로 돌아가는 것도 불가능하다.
Not that I will gain my human form again neither.
Akupun juga tidak akan bisa kembali ke wujud manusiaku lagi.
그러나 지금은 그 답을 확실하게 알겠다. 그것은, 켄토, 너다.
But now, I know the right answer. That is... you. Kento.
Namun, sekarang aku tahu pasti jawabannya. Itu... demi dirimu, Kento.
나?
Me?
Demi aku?
나는 항상 켄토를 보아 왔다.
I have always been watching you, Kento.
Dari dulu, aku selalu mengamatimu.
매지컬 게이트가 데리트로스에게 침략을 당하기 전부터.
Even before Magical Gate become invaded by Deletloss.
Bahkan sebelum Magical Gate diambil alih oleh Deletloss.
나와 비슷한 구석이 있었다. 오래 전의 내 자신을 보는 기분이었다.
You had something similar to me. It felt like watching myself long time ago.
Ada sesuatu pada dirimu yang mirip denganku. Rasanya seperti melihat aku yang dulu.
그래서 나는 켄토를 웹다이버로 선택하고 싶다고 생각했다.
That's why I wanted to choose you as my Webdiver.
Mungkin, karena itu aku memilihmu sebagai Webdiverku.
날 글라디온이 고른 거라고?
I'm similar to you?
Aku mirip dengan Gladion?
그리고 켄토와 마음이 하나된 때, 나는 나에게 맹세했다.
And when my spirit became one with Kento, I made an oath to myself.
Lalu, ketika jiwaku menjadi satu denganmu, aku membuat sumpah dengan diriku sendiri.
켄토의 미래는 내가 끝까지 지키겠다고.
I will protect Kento's future to the end.
Aku pasti akan melindungi masa depan Kento hingga akhir.
결코 나처럼 데리트로스에게 미래를 빼앗기게 하지 않겠다고.
I will not let Deletloss take the future away like he did to me.
Aku tak akan membiarkan Deletloss mengambil masa depanmu seperti yang ia lakukan padaku.
글라디온.
Gladion.
알아 줬으면 한다, 켄토. 이 전투로 모든 게 끝날 것이다.
Please understand, Kento. Everything will end with this battle.
Aku mohon pengertianmu, Kento. Semuanya akan selesai dengan pertarungan ini.
그러나 이 전투는 네 미래를 빼앗아갈지도 모른다.
But this battle might also take your future away and end you too.
Tapi, pertarungan ini mungkin akan mengambil masa depanmu.
그럼 의미가 없다. 그 누구도 데리트로스에게 희생되면 안 된다. 안 그러니, 켄토?
That would make everything we've gone through meaningless.
Kalau begitu, semuanya jadi tak ada artinya. Siapapun tak boleh lagi menjadi korban Deletloss. Bukankah begitu, Kento?
Nobody shall be sacrificed to Deletloss. Isn't that right, Kento?
그게...
Urm...
Itu...
켄토. 그러니까 널 데려갈 수는 없다.
Kento. And that's why I can't take you with me.
Kento. Karena itu, aku tidak bisa membawamu.
그래도 걱정할 필요는 없다.
But you do not have to worry.
Tapi, kau tidak perlu khawatir.
네, 그리고 지구 모두의 미래는 반드시 내가 끝까지 지킬 테니까.
I will protect you and everybody over the earth to the end.
Aku akan melindungi masa depanmu dan masa depan semua yang ada di bumi sampai detik terakhir.
글라디온!
Gladion!
데리트로스는 무슨 일이 일어나더라도 쓰러뜨려 줄 테니까.
Whatever happens to me, I will take Deletloss down.
Apapun yang terjadi, aku akan mengalahkan Deletloss.
가지 마, 글라디온! 가면 안 돼!
Don't go, Gladion! You can't go!
Jangan pergi, Gladion! Kau tak boleh pergi!
제발 가지 마!
Please don't leave me!
Kumohon, jangan pergi!
작별이다! 내 웹다이버, 유우키 켄토! 내 친구여!
Farewell, my Webdiver, Yuuki Kento! Dear my friend!
Selamat tinggal, Webdiverku, Yuuki Kento! Temanku!
기다리고 있다, 글라디온!
How long do I have to wait for you, Gladion?
Aku sudah menunggu, Gladion!
글라디온! 글라디온!
Gladion! Gladion!
왜, 대체 왜 그랬어...
Why did you do that...
Kenapa? Kenapa?!
-형...
-켄토...
-Brother...
-Kento...
-Kakak...
행성 쿠리아. 내가 탄생한 곳. 그리고 내가 직접 파괴한 행성.
Planet Kuria. The place where I was born. And the place that I destroyed myself.
Planet Kuria. Tempat dimana aku lahir, dan tempat yang kuhancurkan sendiri.
절대 용서할 수 없다, 데리트로스.
We will never forgive you, Deletloss.
Kami tidak akan memaafkanmu, Deletloss.
잘도, 잘도 우리를!
How dare you did this to us!
Berani-beraninya kau melakukan ini pada kami!
나타났는가. 쿠리아 멸망과 함께 육체를 잃은 전뇌공간에 갇혀버린 혼 녀석들.
Hmph, so you are welcoming me? What a miserable spirits
Muncul juga. Jiwa-jiwa yang terjebak di dunia maya setelah kehilangan badannya bersama dengan kehancuran Kuria.
trapped in the cyber space after losing the bodies.
나에게 없는 것. 그것은 인간의 마음. 마음에서 나오는 분노. 원한. 악의 힘.
The thing that I do not have is human's spirit.
Hal yang kurang dariku adalah hati manusia. Dari hati terciptalah amarah, benci. Kekuatan jahat.
Rage from their spirit. Hatred from their spirit. The power of evil.
자, 너희들은 나를 증오하고 원망하고 그리고 나에게 진화의 힘을 줄지어다!
Now you shall freely detest, show hatred, and give me the power to evolve!
Nah, marahlah dan bencilah padaku! Berikan padaku kekuatan untuk berevolusi!
이것이 데이터노이드.
This is Datanoid.
Jadi ini Datanoid.
결국, 결국엔 내 때가 왔다. 이제 남은 건 이 전뇌세계에서 탈출해 현실 세계 파괴의 길을 여는 것뿐.
Finally, it's the time.
Akhirnya, aku telah lepas! Sekarang, tinggal keluar dari dunia maya ini dan mulai menghancurkan dunia nyata!
The only thing remaining is to get out of this cyber world and start destructing the real world.
이걸로 준비는 끝났다!
Every preparations are complete!
Dengan ini, semua persiapannya telah terkumpul!
거기까지다! 데리트로스!
That's as far as you go, Deletloss!
Sampai di situ saja, Deletloss!
왔는가, 글라디온?
You're late, Gladion.
Datang juga, Gladion.
널 현실 세계에 가도록 둘 수는 없다!
I will stop you from going to the real world!
Tak akan kubiarkan kau pergi ke dunia nyata!
멍청한 것. 웹다이버도 없이 데이터노이드에 동화한 나에게 이길 수 있다 생각하나?
Nonsense. You cannot defeat me in a form of Datanoid without a Webdiver.
Omong kosong. Apa kau bisa menang melawanku dalam wujud Datanoid sementara tak ada Webdiver yang menemanimu?
이번에야말로 숨줄을 끊어주겠다. 이 인연의 땅, 행성 쿠리아에서!
I will cut your life this time, in this planet Kuria, the land of destiny!
Akan kulenyapkan jiwamu kali ini, di tanah penentu ini, planet Kuria!
켄토...
Kento...
아니야.
That's not it.
Bukan itu.
아니야! 틀렸어!
No! That's so wrong!
Tidak! Itu salah!
그게 아니야! 글라디온은 나한테 말했어.
He's wrong! Gladion told me before.
Kau salah! Gladion tadi bilang padaku.
더 이상 누구도 데리트로스에게 희생되게 할 수 없다고!
He said that nobody shall be sacrificed to Deletloss any more!
Katanya, "Siapapun tak boleh lagi menjadi korban Deletloss"!
근데 지금은 우리는 그 때문에 글라디온을 희생하고 있어.
But we're now sacrificing Gladion because of that.
Tapi, sekarang, kita mengorbankan Gladion untuk itu.
틀렸어! 그런 건 완전히 틀린 거야!
He's wrong! What he said is bullshit!
Itu tidak benar! Semua itu pasti salah!
형...
Brother...
Kakak...
난 싫어. 소중한 친구가 우릴 위해 생명을 걸고 싸우고 있는데 우린 닥치고 바라보고 있으라니.
I hate this. I hate to shut up and just watch when my best friend is fighting risking his life.
Aku tidak suka ini. Aku tidak bisa diam saja dan hanya melihat sahabatku bertarung mempertaruhkan nyawanya begitu saja.
난 그런 건 할 수 없어! 난 갈 거야! 글라디온이 있는 곳에! 그리고 반드시 데리트로스를 쓰러뜨리고 돌아올 거야!
I will not let this go on! I will go! I will meet Gladion! We will take Deletloss down, and we will come back!
Aku tidak bisa melakukan itu! Aku akan pergi menemui Gladion! Lalu, kami pasti akan mengalahkan Deletloss dan kembali!
둘이서!
Together!
Bersama-sama!
잘 말했어, 켄토!
Well said, Kento!
Ucapan yang bagus, Kento!
대체 저 데리트로스 아이를 넘어가면 뭐가 있을까?
What will be there, over that Deletloss Eye?
Apa yang sebenarnya ada di balik Deletloss Eye itu?
이게 무슨!
No way!
Mustahil!
저길 넘으면 또다른 네트워크... 그러니까 우주 전체를 넘나드는 네트워크야.
Over that, there's an another network... the network expanding through the whole Space.
Di balikitu, ada jaringan lain... jaringan yang meluas hingga ke seluruh luar angkasa.
대체 누가 이런 걸...
Who the heck would make such thing...
Siapa yang membuat hal seperti ini...
아마... 미지의 지적 생명체, 외계인이 만들었을 거야뾰꼬.
Maybe... an unknown sentient being, an alien have made that-pyoko.
Mungkin, makhluk tak dikenal, atau alien yang membuatnya-pyoko.
어떻게 이런 미로같은 네트워크를 통해 글라디온이 있는 곳까지 가지?
How can we reach Gladion through this maze-like network?
Bagaimana kita bisa pergi ke tempat Gladion melalui jaringan yang seperti labirin ini?
제가 안내하죠.
I will lead him.
Aku akan memandunya.
엔제!
Enge!
글라디온은 몇 번이고 매지컬 게이트를 위기에서 구해 주었습니다.
Gladion has saved Magical Gate from crisis for hundreds of times.
Gladion telah sering menyelamatkan Magical Gate dari bahaya.
이번엔 제가 그의 힘이 되어 줄 차례입니다.
Now, it's time for me to become his strength.
Ini adalah saatnya bagiku untuk menjadi kekuatannya.
고마워, 엔제.
Thank you, Enge.
Terima kasih, Enge.
자, 갑시다.
Now, let's go.
Nah, ayo kita pergi.
힘내, 켄토!
Be victorious, Kento!
Berjuanglah, Kento!
이건...?
What's this?
Ini...
그대의 글라디온을 향한 마음이 만들어낸 날개입니다.
They are the wings that your mind to Gladion have made.
Itu adalah sayap yang dibuat dari perasaanmu terhadap Gladion.
잊었습니까? 켄토.
Did you forget, Kento?
Apa kau lupa, Kento?
여긴 매지컬 게이트. 아이들의 희망이 현실이 되는 곳이에요.
You're in Magical Gate, where children's wishes come true.
Ini adalah Magical Gate, dimana keinginan anak-anak menjadi kenyataan.
그랬구나!
That's right!
Begitu!
매지컬 스테이션이...!
Magical Station is being...!
Magical Station diserang!
샤이닝 볼트!
Shining Bolt!
쟌! 가륜!
Jean! Garyun!
매지컬 스테이션은 우리가 지킬게! 켄토, 넌 글라디온이 있는 곳으로 서둘러 가!
We'll protect Magical Station! Kento, you just go help Gladion as fast as you can!
Kami akan melindungi Magical Station! Kento, cepatlah pergi ke tempat Gladion!
알았어! 정말 고마워!
Got it! Thank you so much!
Aku mengerti! Terima kasih!
-가자! 가륜!
-좋아!
-Let's go! Garyun!
-Got it!
-Ayo, Garyun!
-Baiklah!
샤이닝 볼트!
Shining Bolt!
이걸로 끝장이다, 글라디온!
This is your end, Gladion!
Inilah akhir untukmu, Gladion!
좀만 기다려, 글라디온! 지금 가고 있으니까!
Please wait for me, Gladion! I'm coming for you!
Tunggulah aku, Gladion! Aku akan menyusulmu!
Screenplay
Kubota Masashi
Storyboarding
Staging
Okajima Kunitoshi
Oda Yoshihiro
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Kobayashi Yumiko
Gladion
Sugita Tomokazu
Arisugawa Aoi
Kikuchi Shiho
Asaba Naoki
Takeuchi Junko
Kurachi Shou
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Jean J. Jekyll
Nakai Masataka
Yuuki Kaito
Takagi Reiko
Yuuki Taketo
Ookura Masaaki
Yuuki Natsuko
Kawasaki Eriko
Arisugawa Professor
Tobita Nobuo
Kurachi Rena
Kakazu Yumi
Sakuraba Kouji
Maekawa Yuuko
Voice Actor
Enge
Uchikawa Ai
Garyun
Konishi Katsuyuki
Deletloss
Tachiki Fumiko
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Oikawa Neko
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kouno Yougo
Singer
Kageyama Hironobu
Insert Song
Lyrics
Composer
Arranger
Kyouda Seiichi
Singer
Insert Song
SYNC ~because you exists~
Lyrics
Takatori Hideaki
Composer
Hirama Akihiko
Arranger
Singer
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
Thank you for watching!
Production
다음 이야기 미리보기
Preview for Next Episode
Episode Selanjutnya
백만 년의 시간을 넘어 모든 것이 시작된 행성 쿠리아.
Planet Kuria, where everything started before million years ago.
Planet Kuria, dimana semua dimlulai sejuta tahun yang lalu.
고된 일도, 슬픈 일도, 기쁜 일도... 다양한 일이 있었어.
Tough things, sad things, happy things... many things happened.
Hal yang susah, sedih, dan senang... banyak hal sudah terjadi.
그 중에서도 너하고 만난 일이 제일 행복했어.
Among them, meeting you was the happiest thing ever happened to me.
Namun, bertemu denganmu merupakan hal terbaik yang terjadi padaku.
둘도 없는 내 소중한 친구, 글라디온.
My irreplaceable best friend, Gladion.
Sahabatku yang tiada duanya, Gladion.
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 마지막 이야기!
Last episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Episode terakhir dari Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !